(COYOTE HOWLING)
(GUNSHOTS FIRING)
(GROANS)
You're from Baker?
Tell Baker that
I told him all
that I know already.
Tell him I want
to live in peace,
understand?
There is no use to
go on tormenting me!
I know nothing at all
about that case of coins.
Now that gold
has disappeared,
but if he'd listened,
we could have
avoided this altogether.
I went to the army court.
There were no witnesses.
They couldn't
uncover any more.
I can't tell Baker
what happened to the money.
Go back and tell him that.
Word's around
you had a visitor,
and Baker knows it.
Name of Jackson.
Well, Jackson was here
or Baker's got it all wrong.
He's not wrong.
Maybe Baker
would like to know
just what you and
Jackson had to say
about the cash box.
That's not what
I'm being paid for.
I'm only interested in
what name Jackson's
hiding under now.
Why do you think
Jackson may be
assuming another name?
I would have
found him already.
When I start off
to find somebody,
I find him.
That's why they pay me.
What is Baker paying you?
That your family?
Yes.
(CHUCKLES)
Nice family.
What does he pay
you for murdering me?
$500
to get the name.
The name.
Carson. Bill Carson.
That's what
he calls himself now.
That's a lot of money. $1 ,000.
$1 ,000?
And some in gold.
That's a tidy sum.
But when I'm paid,
I always see the job through.
(SNORING)
It's you.
Any information?
Too much.
He said quite a bit
that should interest you,
and one or two
things that interested me.
Such as?
The name Jackson's
hiding under is Bill Carson.
Ah.
That's your bit.
Keep talking.
He also mentioned something
about a certain cash box,
which just
happened to disappear.
That's my bit.
Anything else?
Not enough for you, eh?
Well, you don't have to worry.
He'll never say
anything to anybody again.
Oh, yeah, yeah. Perfect.
Here you are.
Here. This is for you.
You did a good job for me.
Worth $500.
(COUGHS)
Yeah. I almost forgot.
He gave me $1 ,000.
I think his idea
was that I kill you.
(LAUGHING)
But you know the pity is,
when I'm paid,
I always follow
my job through.
You know that.
No! Angel Eyes. . .
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
No. No pistol, amigo.
It won't do you any good.
There are three of us.
Hey, amigo.
You know you've got
a face beautiful enough
to be worth $2,000?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Yeah.
But you don't look
like the one
who'll collect it.
A couple steps back.
Thank you.
How much are
you worth now?
How much?
$2,000.
That's right, $2,000.
Yeah, $2,000.
(LAUGHING)
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
You'll pay for this!
I hope you end up
in a graveyard
with the cholera
and the rabies
and the plague!
Cut me loose!
Cut me loose,
you filthy bastard !
Put me down !
I hope your mother ends up
in a two-dollar whorehouse!
Cut me loose!
You can still
save yourself.
Let me go,
and I'll pardon you.
Let me go.
I think I feel sick.
The blood is
bursting through my. . .
I'm dry, Blondie.
Water.
(LAUGHING)
You swine.
You son of a bitch.
Let me go!
You're brave with
a man who's tied up!
Come back!
Come back and fight!
You bastard.
TUCO: Who the hell is that?
One bastard goes in,
another comes out.
Cut it out!
I'm an honest farmer!
I'm innocent of any. . .
So, you're an honest farmer.
You recognize this man?
Me?
Yeah, it's you.
Me? Who says so?
You can't even read.
Yeah, roll it up.
Roll it up.
I'll give you a good idea
where you can put it.
To hell with all you
sheriffs and deputies and
all who gave birth to you.
Hey, everybody, look, look.
He's giving him
the filthy money.
Judas. You sold my hide.
But you won't enjoy
any of that money,
not a penny.
If there's
justice in the world,
that money will go
to the undertakers.
Every penny of it.
You know who you are?
You want to know
whose son you are?
You don't, I do.
Everybody does.
You're the son of
a thousand fathers,
all bastards like you.
And your mother. . .
Your mother!
She's. . . You bastard !
Your mother. . .
It's better not
to talk of her!
I never hurt anybody!
MAN: "Wanted in 1 4
counties of this state,
"the condemned is found guilty
of the crimes of murder,
"armed robbery of citizens,
state banks and post offices,
"the theft of sacred objects,
arson in a state prison,
"perjury, bigamy, deserting
his wife and children,
"inciting prostitution,
kidnapping, extortion,
"receiving stolen goods,
selling stolen goods,
"passing counterfeit money,
and contrary to
the laws of this state,
"the condemned is guilty
of using marked cards
and loaded dice."
Therefore, according to
the powers vested in us,
we sentence
the accused here before us
Tuco Benedicto Pacifico
Juan Maria Ramirez. . .
Known as "The Rat."
. . .and any other
aliases he might have
to hang by the neck
until dead.
May God have
mercy on his soul.
Proceed.
(GRUNTS)
Five for you. One, two
three, four, five for me.
Five for you
and five for me.
Know how much
you're worth now?
No. How much?
$3,000.
There are two kinds of people
in the world, my friend,
those with a rope
around their neck,
and the people
who have the job
of doing the cutting.
Listen, the neck at
the end of the rope is mine.
I run the risks.
So the next time,
I want more than half.
You may run the risks,
my friend,
but I do the cutting.
If we cut down
my percentage. . .
Cigar?
It's liable
to interfere with my aim.
But if you miss,
you had better
miss very well.
Whoever double crosses me
and leaves me alive,
he understands
nothing about Tuco.
(CHUCKLES)
Nothing.
MAN: "Wanted in 1 5
counties of this state.
"The condemned
standing before us,"
sitting before us,
"Tuco Benedicto Pacifico
Juan Maria Ramirez,
has been found guilty
"by the Third District
Circuit Court of
the following crimes,
"murder, assaulting
a justice of the peace,
"raping a virgin
of the white race,
"statutory rape
of a minor of the black race,
"derailing a train in order
to rob the passengers. . ."
Hey, Angel Eyes.
". . .bank robbery,
highway robbery,
"robbing an unknown number of
post offices, breaking out. . ."
What'd you
find out, Shorty?
If you ask me,
it seems like a book.
An armed unit escorting
a cash box of gold coins
meets a Yankee ambush,
and only three
of them are saved.
Stevens, Baker
and Jackson.
The thing that wasn't saved,
though, was the coins.
But then the army decides,
of course,
it ought to hold a hearing,
and Jackson's acquitted.
He disappears and
becomes Bill Carson.
I know his name.
But you don't know just who
you're looking for, and I do.
And when he's found,
I'd be scared to be
put in his shoes.
Where is Carson?
All I know is
Carson reenlisted.
The poor guy's minus an eye.
He lives with a girl
called Maria who'll tell you.
She's a fresh young
whore in the territory.
Where's she?
Now, what's the
name of that town?
Someplace fairly near.
Santa Ana.
Adios, half-soldier.
Hey, Luke, hand me
down a whiskey.
MAN: ". . .and the sheriff's
office in Sonora.
"The condemned
hired himself out
as a guide to a wagon train.
"After receiving his
payment in advance,
he deserted the wagon train
"on the hunting grounds
of the Sioux Indians."
Glad they got him,
a man guilty of
all those crimes.
People with ropes
around their necks
don't always hang.
What do you mean?
"The condemned
is also guilty. . ."
Even a filthy beggar like that
has got a protecting angel.
MAN: ". . .as a
Mexican general."
A golden-haired angel
watches over him.
"For all these crimes,
"the accused has made a full,
spontaneous confession.
"Therefore, we condemn him
to be hung by the neck
until dead."
May the Lord have
mercy on his soul.
Proceed.
Let's get the hell
out of here!
TUCO:
What are you trying to say,
anybody can miss a shot?
Nobody misses when
I'm at the end of the rope.
You've never had
a rope around your neck.
Well, I'm going to
tell you something.
When that rope
starts to pull tight,
you can feel
the devil bite your ass.
Yeah, you're right.
It's getting tougher.
The way I figure,
there's really
not too much future
with a sawed-off
runt like you.
What do you mean?
'Cause I don't think
you'll ever be worth
more than $3,000.
What do you mean?
I mean,
our partnership is untied.
Oh, no. Not you.
You remain tied.
I'll keep the money,
and you can have the rope.
You filthy,
double-crossing bastard !
Of all the stinking,
dirty tricks. . .
The way back to
town is only 70 miles.
You know,
if you save your breath,
I feel a man like
you could manage it.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
You filthy bastard !
Come here!
Cut this rope off!
Get off that horse.
Get off that horse,
you filthy coward !
If I ever catch you,
Blondie, I'll rip your
heart out and eat it!
I'll scalp you !
I'll skin you alive!
I'll hang you up
by your thumbs!
You pig ! You vulture!
I'll kill you !
Such ingratitude,
after all the times
I've saved your life.
Where are you going?
Wait a minute.
This is only a trick.
You wouldn't leave me here.
Come back! Wait! Blondie!
Listen, Blondie. . .
(SCREAMING IN SPANISH)
(MEN SINGING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
MAN: I believe
madam is home.
Sweet dreams, and many thanks
from the Seventh Cavalry!
You filthy rats!
MAN: Maria.
Honey?
Is that you, Bill?
Bill.
(SHRIEKS)
Who are you?
What do you
want with me?
Go on talking
about Bill Carson.
I don't know him.
You were calling
to him in the dark.
Where is he?
What are you
going to do to him?
I'll ask the questions.
Where is he?
(GROANS)
Where is he? Where?
Where? Where? Where?
That's enough !
I don't know where he is.
He packed his things
ten days ago
and went away with
his unit. They all left.
Which company?
Where'd they go?
Hmm?
Third Cavalry,
General Sibley.
They left for Santa Fe.
That's all I know, I swear!
(GASPING)
But, but. . .
I'm very sorry,
but the store's closing.
Mmm-hmm.
(CHUCKLES)
Revolvers.
Yeah, revolvers.
Well, here's where
I keep the best ones.
Here. Remington, Colt,
a Roat, Smith-Wesson,
Colt, Navy,
Joslyn, another Remington.
And this one is. . .
That's enough.
Cartridges.
You want to try the pistol?
Just step out back.
Let's go.
Move. Move.
(LAUGHING)
Cartridge.
How much?
$20.
(LAUGHS)
No.
$50.
How much?
$1 00
$200.
It's all I've got.
Here.
Come here.
(LAUGHS)
Eh?
Mmm-hmm.
TUCO: If you work for
a living, why do you
kill yourself  working?
(SCOFFS)
Potatoes.
You've got to be
poor to eat potatoes.
Really poor.
I'm rich. But I'm lonely.
The world is divided
into two parts,
those who have friends,
and those who are lonely,
like poor Tuco.
You see, I used
to have a friend, Pedro.
Chico and Ramon,
his two brothers,
were my friends, too.
But who knows
where they are now?
It's too bad, friends.
Tough luck
I haven't found you.
I had a good deal for you.
There's a big
son of a bitch
who's got $4,000.
$4,000.
And I know
where to find it.
If they would
help me catch him,
I'd divide it four ways,
like a brother.
$1 ,000 each.
Hmm.
You're alive, Tuco.
Is it true?
And rich.
Like you're going to be.
But people are saying
you got killed in Albuquerque.
And people talk bullshit.
I'm alive, you bastards,
and I always will be.
And I've come to
give you $3,000.
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
This morning,
I heard the whole thing.
They say Colonel Canby's
closing in with
his Northerners,
and no later than tomorrow
that they'll be in the city.
That's why
these Southerners
are getting out.
You see, as soon as these
cowards hear a Blue Shirt's
around, they run.
These Rebels have
no will to fight.
WOMAN:
Poor things.
They'll soon be finished.
We get rid of these bastards,
then we begin making money
on those Yankees.
They carry gold,
not paper dollars,
and they're going
to beat the South.
Look. See that one
with the white beard
sitting in the wagon?
General Sibley.
He looks dead.
He's finally
getting out of our hair.
Hurray for Dixie!
Hurray! Hurray for Dixie!
Where's the owner
of that horse?
Please, mister, sir,
a bad heart condition. . .
Where?
The war has
frightened me already.
I'm looking for the
owner of that horse.
He's tall, blond,
he smokes a cigar,
and he's a pig.
Where is he now?
You leave him be.
He doesn't know who
rides every horse.
You stay quiet, old hen.
Upstairs. Upstairs
in room four, señor.
Hear that?
You rotten criminals.
How dare you?
(SPURS CLINKING)
(SPURS CLINK)
(DISTANT CANNONS FIRING)
Your spurs.
(SPUR CLINKING)
(TUCO LAUGHS)
There are two kinds
of spurs, my friend,
those that come
in by the door,
in by the window.
Take off that pistol belt.
It's empty.
Mine isn't.
(CANNONS FIRING)
Even when Judas
hanged himself,
there was a storm, too.
That could be cannon fire.
Cannon fire or storm,
it's all the same to you.
You ever see this
before, my friend?
Throw it over
the roof beam.
That's it.
Now get on that.
That's right.
Now make sure
the rope is tight.
It's got to hold
the weight of a pig.
Now put the rope
around your neck.
That's very good.
It's too big
for your neck, huh?
We fix that right away.
I have another system,
a little different than yours.
I don't shoot the rope.
I shoot the legs
off the stool.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GRUNTS)
(COUGHS)
Welcome, my friend.
If you're looking for
a summer vacation spot,
you've found it.
Our hotel is luxurious
and filled with conveniences.
(ALL LAUGHING)
And the attractions
don't stop there.
International cuisine,
healthful and nutritious food.
Corn cobs, Dixie-style.
Our government has
spared no expense.
As you can see,
we are treated very well.
Have you ever
heard of anyone
by the name
of Bill Carson?
And you? Have you ever heard
of someone named Canby? No?
Well, you see,
he's a Yankee colonel
who decided to
tear us to pieces.
The only thing we care about
is saving our own hides.
And you ask me
if I know someone.
I just don't know
what you drifters
could be thinking.
Carson has a patch
over one eye.
He's with the Third.
If he's with the Third,
they've already left.
For Glorieta.
Canby's front line is
right on their heels.
Those poor young devils.
And the desert
lies ahead of them.
I really doubt that
any of them are still alive.
And what if they
were still alive?
Worse.
Well, then, you must
not have heard anything
about Batterville.
It's one of those
Yankee prison camps
you'd better hope
you never end up in.
Keep it.
It's yours.
"We have found the accused,
Thomas Larson,
alias Shorty Larson,
"guilty of
the following crimes,
"horse theft,
theft of supplies
belonging to the Union Army,
"theft of supplies belonging
to the Confederate Army,
"wounding two vigilantes,
"assault and battery on
one named Barry O'Keefe,
"perjury, blackmail, robbery,
"escaping from a state prison,
"disturbing the peace,
pandering, highway robbery. . ."
And Shorty?
". . .forgery and murder."
Therefore,
with the powers vested in us
by the laws of this state. . .
No.
No?
. . .we have condemned
the aforementioned
Thomas Larson,
alias Shorty Larson, to hang
by the neck until dead.
May God have mercy
on his soul. Proceed.
(SCREAMS)
Sorry, Shorty.
Move. Come on, let's go.
I don't know.
As soon as I hit
the desert, I'm thirsty.
Burns, huh? They say
people with fair skin
can't take too much.
Like that,
you won't have
to carry so much.
Where we going?
Where?
Where I'm going, amigo.
Over that way.
Another 1 00 miles
of beautiful, sunbaked sand.
Even the armies are afraid
to march through there.
Sibley's men are
retreating up there.
Canby's men are coming here.
But no one will set
foot in this hell,
except you and me.
1 00 miles,
that's a nice walk.
What was it you
told me the last time?
"If you save your breath,
I feel a man like
you could manage it."
And if you won't manage it,
you'll die, only slowly,
very slowly, old friend.
After you, please.
Start walking.
Taking a rest?
Come on, Blondie.
We don't have
very far to go.
Only 70 miles.
Only eight-and-a-half hours
more before sunset.
That's not too bad.
Come on.
(LAUGHING)
Okay, let's eat.
That is, I'll eat.
Hmm?
Meanwhile, you can
enjoy a sunbath.
You want some water?
Drink. Drink.
Come on. Come on.
Well, Blondie. So long.
And so, Blondie,
it's goodbye.
(RUMBLING)
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. Whoa, boy.
Easy, easy. Easy, easy.
Attaboy. That's nice.
Water. Water.
$200,000 in gold.
It's yours.
Just get me water.
What's that you say?
Who the hell are you?
Carson.
My name is
Bill Carson now.
It's Carson.
Surprise attack.
All dead. My name is
Jackson, not Carson.
Carson, Carson, yeah, yeah.
Glad to meet you, Carson.
I'm Lincoln's grandfather.
What was that you
said about the dollars?
$200,000, all mine.
Was the Third Cavalry's.
Baker has nothing.
The gold, I hid the gold.
The gold is safe.
Where? Where, here?
Here? Talk.
In the cemetery.
Which cemetery?
The one on Sad Hill.
There's a grave by. . .
Which grave?
Have a name?
Have a number?
Come on, you dummy, talk.
There's no number.
There's a name.
It's written. . .
Yes?
(CHOKING)
Water.
You talk first, huh?
I'll give you water later.
Sad Hill Cemetery. Okay.
In the grave. Okay.
But it must have a name
or a number on it, huh?
There must be a
thousand, five thousand.
Don't die, huh?
Don't die.
I'll get you water.
Stay there. Don't move.
Don't die until later,
you son of a. . .
(SCREAMS)
Get away from there.
He's dead.
Yeah.
I'll kill you.
If you do that,
you'll always be poor,
just like the greasy
rat that you are.
If I were you,
I'd keep me alive.
What did he tell you, huh?
A name.
A name on a grave.
What name?
Blondie, don't die.
I'm your friend.
Please don't die. Please.
Come on. Come on.
Blondie.
I'll help you.
Don't move.
I'll be right back.
Here's the water.
Don't die like that pig.
Hey, Blondie,
here's water.
Water, Blondie.
Don't drink, don't drink.
Is no good for you.
Feel better?
Blondie,
what's the matter?
Please, don't die.
TUCO: Hey, open up!
Open up! Hurry!
Settle down.
Who's there?
What do you mean,
"Who's there?"
You think I'm the enemy?
If I were a Yankee,
you wouldn't have
time to ask me that.
Come on.
Sergeant, listen to
this corporal for a moment.
Yes, sir.
Sergeant,
I have a gravely
wounded man here,
if he's not dead already.
He's still alive?
Well, he seems to be.
What happened?
It was a trap.
Only the two
of us got away.
Name and traveling papers.
Here. Corporal Bill Carson.
Third Regiment,
2nd Cavalry Squadron,
arriving from San Rafael.
Is that enough?
Are you reading
when this man is dying?
Why, Corporal,
we're trying to withdraw
and you're looking
for an infirmary?
If you want one, you'll
have to make yourself
a Yankee prisoner.
(ALL LAUGHING)
So where are we?
Near Apache Canyon.
Apache Canyon?
Apache Canyon.
Is a Mission San Antonio
around here?
Sure, 1 8 miles south.
Take him there.
The brothers take care
of anyone who's wounded,
no matter what
the color of his uniform.
And keep your eyes open,
the area is full of Yankees.
Thank you.
Goodbye, Sergeant.
Take care.
I've got a very
sick man here.
But we have no
more beds here.
Let him have yours.
Where's Pablo Ramirez?
Father Ramirez.
He's away at the moment.
He should be back any day now.
Well, it doesn't matter.
For the moment,
we take very good
care of my friend.
And may God be praised.
In case you didn't know it,
God is on our side, too,
because he hates
the Yanks, huh, Blondie?
Blondie? Father,
is he still breathing?
Yes, of course.
TUCO: You're heavy.
There.
All right,
put a fresh
bandage on him.
Put him in my cell.
Easy.
PRIEST: Out, soldier.
Out you go. Come on.
Look out for him, please.
He's like a brother to me.
Hey, Father, I. . .
Father, did he speak?
Did he say anything?
Father, did he ask for me?
Did he speak about
anything, Father?
Oh, no, he hasn't
spoken as yet.
But you mustn't worry.
He's both young and strong.
That's what's kept
him going until now.
He should regain
his strength in
a very short time.
Thank you, Father.
Thank you.
You don't know how much
this boy's life means to me.
Thanks be to Jesus.
Thanks to all of you.
Blondie.
Hey, Blondie.
The old father tells me
you'll be up and
around in a few days.
You're very lucky
to have me so close
when it happened.
Think if you'd
been on your own.
Look, I mean, when. . .
When one is ill,
it's good to have
somebody close by,
friends or relations.
Do you have parents,
Blondie? A mother?
Not even a mother.
No one?
You're all alone, huh?
Like me, Blondie.
We're all alone
in the world.
I have you, you have me.
Only for
a little while, I mean.
It had to happen now.
What a dirty,
rotten trick of fate.
We could have all that
money in our hands.
I must tell you
the truth, Blondie.
In my place, you would
do the same thing.
It's all over for you now.
There's nothing
anyone can do anymore.
God help me. It's my fault.
Mine, mine, mine, mine.
I'll tell you
one thing, Blondie.
If I knew that
my last hour had come, I swear
in my place, in your place,
I would do the same thing.
I would tell
about the gold.
Yes. Yes, I would.
I'd tell the name
on the grave.
After all,
what good is the money
to you if you're dead?
I know the name
of the cemetery,
but you know
how many graves
there are there?
Please, Blondie.
Please, have a little, huh?
Here. Coffee.
Please, tell me the name
on the grave.
If I get my hands
on the $200,000,
I'll always
honor your memory.
I swear, I'll always
(WHISPERS)
Come closer.
Tell me.
Why, you dirty. . .
I'll sleep better
knowing my good
friend is by my side
to protect me.
"Tuco, water."
Well, here's water.
But if I get
that name from you,
I'll give you water.
All right, you dirty skunk,
get your ass off the bed.
Come on, come on,
the party's over.
The wagon is
all ready to go.
From the way the wounded
are pouring into this place,
we better get
the hell out of here
before we get
caught up in the war.
Tuco, Father Ramirez is back.
Yeah.
This is something
I have to look into.
It'll only take
a minute. Get moving.
Where, this way?
Yes.
Hey, Pablo.
Don't you recognize me?
It's me, Tuco.
Let me embrace you.
I don't know
the right thing.
I was just passing by here,
I said to myself,
"I wonder if my brother
remembers his brother."
Did I do wrong?
It doesn't matter.
I'm very happy.
You have seen me, Tuco.
Yeah, well,
I'm very glad I came.
Oh, my uniform.
It's a long story.
But let's talk about you.
It's more important.
You look very well.
A bit thin, perhaps, but
(LAUGHS)
you were always thin,
eh, Pablito?
What about our parents?
Only now do you
think of them.
To begin after nine years.
Nine years?
So it's nine years.
Nine years.
Our mother has been dead
a long time now.
Our father died
only a few days ago.
That's why I was away.
He asked for you to be there,
but there was only me.
And you?
Outside of evil,
what else have
you managed to do?
It seems to me
you once had
a wife someplace.
Not one, lots of them.
One here, one there,
wherever I found them.
Go on, preach me
a sermon, Pablo.
What good would that be?
Just keep on
the way you're going.
Go away.
And the Lord have
mercy on your soul.
Sure, I'll go, I'll go.
While I'm waiting
for the Lord
to remember me,
I, Tuco Ramirez,
brother of Brother Ramirez,
will tell you something.
You think you're
better than I am.
Where we came from,
if one didn't want
to die of poverty,
one became
a priest or a bandit.
You chose your way,
I chose mine.
Mine was harder!
You talk about
Mother and Father.
You remember, when you
left to become a priest,
I stayed behind.
I must have been 1 0, 1 2.
I don't remember which,
but I stayed.
I tried, but it was no good.
Now I will tell
you something.
You became a priest because
you were too much of a coward
to do what I do.
Tuco.
Please forgive me, brother.
My belly's full.
Nice guy, my brother.
I didn't tell you
my brother was
in charge here?
Everything.
Like the pope almost.
He's in charge in Rome.
Yeah, yeah, my brother,
he say to me,
"Stay, brother.
Don't go home.
"We never see each other.
"Here there's plenty
to eat and drink.
Bring your friend, too."
Whenever we see each other,
he never lets me go.
It's always the same story.
My brother,
he is crazy about me.
That's so.
Even a tramp like me,
no matter what happens,
I know there's
a brother somewhere
who will never refuse me
a bowl of soup.
Sure.
Well, after a meal,
there's nothing
like a good cigar.
TUCO: Here's the
Sierra Magdalena.
Going this way,
we cross the Rio Grande.
That sure is a long way.
Here to the northwest,
through all of Texas.
After that. . .
Then what?
When we get there,
I'll tell you.
You're not worried, are you?
Those men aren't worried
about anything anymore,
are they?
But since I'm alive
and I've noticed
we'll be crossing Yankee
and Confederate lines
a few times,
I thought you might
tell me where we're going.
Towards $200,000.
Is that good enough for you?
(GRUNTS)
Hey, wake up, you.
The troops are coming.
Come on.
Blue or gray?
They're gray like us.
Let's say "hello" to them
and then get going.
Hoorah ! Hoorah for
the Confederacy!
Hoorah !
Down with General Grant!
Hoorah for General. . .
What's his name?
Lee.
Lee! Lee!
God is with us because
he hates the Yanks, too!
God's not on our side
'cause he hates idiots also.
SOLDIER:
Hut, two, three, four.
Prisoners of war, forward
march !
Halt!
Left face!
Form a single file. Move!
Jonathan Frost!
Present!
Richard McGilley!
Nathaniel Sullivan !
Present.
Robert Clark!
Sam Richmond !
Present.
Bill Carson !
I said Bill Carson !
Hey, Blondie,
isn't that Angel Eyes?
SOLDIER: All right,
what's he doing, sleeping?
Bill Carson !
Yeah, and you
better be Bill Carson.
Bill Carson !
Yeah, that's me.
Please, Carson,
answer "present."
What are you, deaf?
Now suppose you
say "present," Carson.
I like big
fat men like you.
When they fall,
they make more noise,
and sometimes
they never get up.
Wallace,
that's enough.
Sergeant!
The captain wants
to see you right away.
Be sure these two
get good treatment.
Hey, Blondie,
did you hear that?
Good treatment.
Yeah.
For the last time, Sergeant,
I'm telling you,
I want the prisoners
treated as prisoners.
No more brutality.
There's hundreds of
prisoners out there
and only a few
men to guard them.
Now what am I supposed to do?
I have to have respect.
I think that you'll manage
to gain their respect
by treating them better.
Are our men treated that well
in Andersonville camp?
I don't give a God damn
what they do in Andersonville.
While I'm in charge here,
the prisoners are
not to be tortured,
or cheated or murdered.
That an accusation?
Sergeant, gangrene is eating
my leg away, not my eyes.
I know the prisoners here
are being robbed
systematically.
I know there's
scum around who are
bivouacked near the camp
waiting for someone
to deliver this loot.
But as long as I'm commandant,
I won't permit any
such trickery. Am I clear?
Yes.
Just as long as
you're the commandant.
Yes, Sergeant.
I know this leg means
I won't last very long,
but I pray I can manage
to have enough time
to amass evidence
and bring to a court-martial
all those who
discredit and dishonor
the uniform of the Union.
I wish you luck.
You and the others
better lay low
for a few days.
No, I'll keep this. You go.
Wallace will let you know.
Wallace, bring me Carson.
Right.
Listen, Angel Eyes said
for us to lay low
for a few days,
but we'll keep close enough
to keep an eye on things.
Come on, saddle your horses.
Get in.
(DOOR LOCKS)
ANGEL EYES: Come on in, Tuco.
Don't be bashful.
There's no
formalities here.
It's been a long time.
You're hungry.
Sit down, eat.
I knew it, I knew it.
The minute I saw you,
I said to myself,
"Look at that pig,
Angel Eyes.
"I'll bet he got
himself an easy job,
"and he never
forgets a friend."
I never forget
old friends, Tuco.
Right.
It's good to see
old friends again.
Good.
Especially when they've
come from so far away
and have so much
to talk about.
And you do have
a lot to talk about,
haven't you?
You were captured
near Fort Craig.
Well, if you were
with Sibley, that means then
that you were coming
from Santa Fe.
Was it hard
crossing the desert?
Mmm-Hmm. Very hard.
Especially if you don't
have anything to drink.
Why are you going
under the name of
Bill Carson now?
One name is as
good as another.
Not wise to use
your own name.
Like you.
I'll bet they don't
call you Angel Eyes.
Sergeant Angel Eyes.
(LAUGHS)
Like a little music
with your meal, Tuco?
Music? Yes, it's very good,
very good for the digestion.
So. . .
Bill Carson's
a fake name, huh?
That fake, too?
Bill Carson's name's
written in it.
Have some.
It's Bill Carson's tobacco.
(SCREAMS)
(SINGING FOLK SONG)
Was Carson dead or alive
when you found him?
What'd he tell you
about the money?
(CHOKING) I don't. . .
I don't know what
you're talking about.
(SCREAMS)
More feeling.
You can sure
consider yourself
much luckier than your pal.
Wallace will
punch your friend
as long as the song goes.
So many of us have
had a session in there.
How's your digestion now?
You'd better talk.
I have nothing to tell you.
Play that fiddle, you.
(SCREAMING)
TUCO: Enough.
Enough. I talk. I talk.
What did he say
about the money?
It's buried in a grave.
Where?
Sad Hill.
Sad Hill Cemetery.
Which grave?
I don't know.
I don't know, I tell you.
Blondie.
Ask Blondie.
He knows the name
on the grave.
Put those clothes on.
Why?
We're going for a ride.
Where?
To find $200,000.
I know the name of
the cemetery now,
and you know
the name of the grave.
You're not gonna give me
the same treatment?
Would you talk?
No, probably not.
That's what I thought.
Not that you're any
tougher than Tuco,
but you're smart
enough to know that
talking won't save you.
And Tuco, is he. . .
No. Not yet.
But he's in
very good hands.
You've changed partners,
but you still
got the same deal.
I'm not greedy.
I'm only taking half.
There's two of us.
It should make it
easier than just one.
Yeah.
Hold it.
That's it, don't move.
Now don't breathe.
Still. That's it.
Got it. Thank you.
Hey, Corporal,
afraid he'll get lost?
Where's the rebel going?
To hell,
with a rope around his neck
and a price on his head.
$3,000, friend.
That's a lot of
money for a head.
I'll bet they
didn't even pay you
a penny for your arm.
(GRUNTS)
I told you once, friend,
if I ever get you down,
you're gonna need
a lot of help
to get up again. A lot.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
You're a lot luckier
than that one there.
You get some trouble, rope,
and you're all finished.
And there isn't
any partner this time
to shoot you down.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
If your friends
stay out in the damp,
they're liable to
catch a cold, aren't they?
Or a bullet.
Hear that, boys?
Come on out here.
Since we're all going
in the same direction,
might as well go together.
One, two, three, four,
five, six.
Six. Perfect number.
Isn't three
the perfect number?
Yeah. But I got six
more bullets in my gun.
(LAUGHS)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(SNORING)
Sure would like to
put your paw on it, huh?
I would like to piss.
It's rough.
I've been shaken up
on this train
nearly ten hours now.
You smell like
a pig already,
but let's not try
to make things any worse.
Get going.
I can't while
you're watching me.
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
You made a lot of noise,
my friend, huh?
You don't want
to break our friendship,
huh? Well, I'll break it.
Halt.
Take your places.
Ready!
Aim ! Fire!
Slim, take care of the horses.
I've been looking for
you for eight months.
Whenever I should've
had a gun in my right hand,
I thought of you.
Now I find you in exactly
the position that suits me.
I had lots of time to learn
how to shoot with my left.
When you have to shoot,
shoot. Don't talk.
Every gun makes its own tune.
It's perfect timing,
Large One.
Clem, follow him.
(TONGUE CLICKING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Just a minute.
I'll be right there.
Just give me a little
time to get dressed,
and I'll open up.
(GUN COCKS)
Put your drawers on
and take your gun off.
Hey, Blondie,
how the hell
did you get out
of that pigsty?
My own way.
I'm here with your
old friend, Angel Eyes.
You talked, you traitor.
You talked.
No, I didn't talk.
If I did, I probably
wouldn't be here now.
You, me. . .
So only you know
your half of the secret?
Mmm-hmm.
Blondie,
I'm very happy
you're working with me,
and we're together again.
I get dressed,
I kill him and
be right back.
Oh, listen,
I forgot to mention,
he's not alone.
There's five of them.
Five?
Yeah, five of them.
So that's why
you came to Tuco?
It doesn't matter.
I'll kill them all.
They shot him
at close range.
Well, look who's here.
The other one
will be along.
They'll come
looking for us.
Watch out.
There's two of them.
I want that blond alive.
You, back there.
Come on, let's go.
Were you gonna die alone?
(WHISTLING CANNONBALL)
(WHISTLES)
Halt!
Hey, Blondie,
Angel Eyes is mine, huh?
All right.
"See you soon. . ."
(STAMMERS)
"Idiots."
It's for you.
How peaceful
and quiet, amigo.
Like a cemetery,
for instance?
There should be
a bridge across that river.
We'd better
wait for nightfall.
Trust in me, Blondie.
I got a good sense
of where I'm going.
Tuco has taken
you this far.
I will take you
all the way. . .
Gentlemen.
Tell the captain.
Yes, sir.
Come along now.
Follow me.
SOLDIER:
We found them near
the perimeter, sir.
Where do you hail from?
Illinois.
And you?
I'm with him.
Any reason for
being around here?
We want to enlist, General.
You better learn
to distinguish rank.
I'm a captain.
Get the hell out.
It sure as hell
might be you today,
so go write your will.
Yes, sir.
So you want to enlist?
You gotta take
a test to prove it.
Well, show me.
(LAUGHS)
You've got a career.
At the least, I'd say
you'll make colonel.
Really?
Sure.
Like it says in the
manual, "You've got
every qualification,
"to become an expert
in the use of weapons."
For this, sir, is
the most potent weapon in war.
The fighting spirit's
in this bottle.
Volunteers.
You want to enlist?
Let's go. Come on,
gentlemen. Come on.
The shooting
hasn't begun yet.
We still have time.
Whoever has the most liquor
to get the soldiers drunk
and send them
to be slaughtered,
is the winner.
We and the ones over
on the other side of the river
only have one thing in common.
All of us reek of alcohol.
What did you
say your name was?
And you?
No.
CAPTAIN:
Names don't matter.
Yes, because
soon you can join
the gallant heroes
of Branson Bridge.
We have two attacks a day.
Two attacks a day?
Sure, the Rebs have
decided that damn bridge
is the key to
this whole area.
Stupid, useless bridge.
Flyspeck on
headquarters' maps.
And headquarters has
declared we must take
that ridiculous flyspeck
even if all of us are killed.
Otherwise,
the key will get rusty
and just be
a spot on the wall.
And that's not all.
Both sides want
the bridge intact.
Intact is how
the South wants it,
and we want it intact, too.
You'll all turn to dust,
but one thing is sure,
boys, Branson Bridge
will stand unbroken.
Is it bad to speak
the way I do
to volunteers?
I've done a lot worse.
I've done it.
I've blown it up. Boom.
In here,
I've destroyed it all.
It's a court-martial
offense to imagine,
to dream of blowing it up.
A serious crime.
Even to think of destroying
that bridge is just. . .
Why not really
blow it up, Captain?
Yeah, Captain,
it's nothing. Let's scare
the hell out of them.
(LAUGHS)
I've been
dreaming about it.
I've even worked
out a plan.
I sure have.
The best time is
after the attack
when there's a truce
to get the wounded.
If I could do it,
I could save many
thousands of men.
But what I lack
is the guts.
They're beginning
their daily slaughter
right on time.
Captain, all companies
are awaiting your orders.
Be right there.
Let's go.
All right, friends,
come along and
enjoy the spectacle.
(TRUMPET BLOWING)
Companies, report!
SOLDIER:
Company B ready!
Company E ready!
SOLDIER:
Company D ready!
Companies, forward !
(CLAMORING)
Hey, Blondie,
it looks like the captain
is really asking for
a bullet in his guts.
Yeah.
I've never seen
so many men
wasted so badly.
I have a feeling
it's really gonna be
a good, long battle.
Blondie?
Huh?
The money's on
the other side
of the river.
Where?
Amigo, I said the other side,
and that's enough.
But while
the Confederates are there,
we can't get across.
What would happen
if somebody were
to blow up that bridge?
Yeah.
Then these idiots would go
somewhere else to fight.
Maybe.
SOLDIER: Doctor, quick,
the captain's wounded.
Hurry, a stretcher.
Easy. Easy now.
Get things ready.
A little of this will help.
Take a slug of this, Captain.
Keep your ears open.
(GRUNTING)
SOLDIER:
What are you doing?
No, leave me alone.
Blondie, you realize
we might be risking our lives.
Yeah, and if I get killed,
you'll never get your hands
on all that beautiful money.
Yeah, Tuco,
it sure would be a pity.
Doc.
Doctor,
could you help me
live a little more?
I expect good news.
Why don't we tell each other
our half of the secret?
Why don't we?
You go first.
No, I think
it's better that
you start.
All right.
The name of
the cemetery is. . .
Sad Hill. Now it's your turn.
The name on the grave is
Arch Stanton.
Arch Stanton?
Are you sure?
Yeah, sure, I'm sure.
(TUCO SCREAMING)
It'll be a lot
easier with that.
Two can dig a lot
quicker than one.
Dig.
You're not digging.
If you shoot me,
you won't see
a cent of that money.
Why?
I'll tell you why.
'Cause there's
nothing in there.
Why, you son of a. . .
You thought I'd trust you?
$200,000 is a lot of money.
We're gonna
have to earn it.
How?
I'll write the name
on the bottom of this stone.
The gun.
You pig. You want
to get me killed?
When'd you unload it?
Last night.
You see, in this world,
there's two kinds
of people, my friend,
those with loaded guns,
and those who dig.
You dig.
Where?
Here.
(TUCO STAMMERS)
There's no name on it!
There's no name
here either.
You see, that's what
Bill Carson told me.
It was the grave
marked "Unknown"
right beside Arch Stanton.
Go ahead.
Blondie!
It's all ours, Blondie.
You're joking, Blondie.
You wouldn't play
a joke on me like that.
It's no joke.
It's a rope, Tuco.
Now I want you
to stand up there
and put your
head in that noose.
Well, now, seems
just like old times.
Four for you
and four. . .
Four for me.
Hey, Blondie.
Sorry, Tuco.
(CHOKING) Blondie. . .
Blondie!
(SCREAMS)
Blondie.
Blondie!
(TUCO CHOKING)
(SCREAMS)
Hey, Blondie!
You know what you are?
Just a dirty son of a bitch !